Brinsley Morrison

SUMMARY

A young enthusiastic and motivated tenor. Currently studying to develop and enhance skills in technique and stagecraft. Experience in ensemble and solo performance as well as having a wide understanding in music, with performed compositions in multiple venues, experience in vocal jazz improvisation and instrumental chamber and orchestral ensembles. Experienced in repertoire from medieval to 21st century.

University of York 07506 213010 contact@brinsleymorrison.com

EDUCATION

2022

Chethams' School of Music

A-Level: **Music** Grade Achieved: **A***

2022

Chethams' School of Music

A-Level: **Music Technology**Grade Achieved: **A***

2022

Chetham's School of Music

A-Level: **English Literature** Grade Achieved: **B**

2022

Chethams' School of Music

ABRSM **Grade 8**Singing: **Distinction**

2021

Chethams' School of Music

ABRSM **Grade 8**Piano: *Merit*

2022

Chethams' School of Music

ABRSM **Grade 8**Violin: *Distinction*

2022

Chethams' School of Music

2017

ABRSM **Grade 5 Music Theory: Distinction**

EXPERIENCE

Soloist with the BBC Philharmonic

Manchester

07/05/2022

Performed the 2nd Tenor solo in Haydn's Harmoniemesse with the BBC Philharmonic Orchestra for Radio 3 in Bridgewater Hall.

This demonstrated my ability to focus and deliver success in an extreme high-pressure environment.

Chethams' School of Music - Quentin Hayes Masterclass

Manchester

03/2022 - 03/2022

Performed a solo for a masterclass with Quentin Hayes looking at stagecraft and German pronunciation.

Chethams' School of Music - February Music Course

Manchester

02/2022 - 02/2022

One week of intensive rehearsals and masterclasses with Oliver Hunt and Libby Burgess. Resulting in a successful unconducted performance of Byrd's Laudibus in Sanctis.

Chethams' School of Music - Wilmslow United Reformed Church Concert

02/2022 - 02/2022

Performed a solo and duet recital in Wilmslow United Reformed Church. Languages sung: English and German

Chethams' School of Music - Vaughn Williams Serenade to Music Concert

Manchester

12/2021 - 12/2021

Performed Vaughn Williams Serenade to Music in collaboration with Royal Northern College of Music soloists.

Chethams' School of Music - Chethams' Chamber Choir

Manchester

09/2020 - 07/2022

A large chamber group performing from early renaissance to 21st century music. Performed 6 times in Stoller Hall.

Chethams' School of Music - Barbershop Choir

Manchester

09/2021 - 02/2022

Setup, organised and sang in a barbershop quartet which performed in The Stoller Hall.

Chethams' School of Music - Solo Lunchtime Concert

Manchester

12/2020 - 12/2020

An Italian-song solo recital of Stradella's Pietà, Signore.

Herefordshire - Lay Clerk at Holy Trinity

01/2018 - 02/2019

Part-time Lay Clerk of Holy Trinity Church, singing services once a week. Performed in St David's Cathedral as an outreach concert.

Hereford - Acafellas

05/2019 - 07/2020

A large acapella group, performing barbershop music in Hereford Cathedral, Holy Trinity Church, and The Courtyard.

Hereford - Hereford Cathedral School Chamber Choir

09/2018 - 07/2020

Performed in remote churches across Wales for the Music in Quiet Places scheme.

Performed as part of Herford Cathedral's Carols for Shoppers event, and with the opening piece of Hereford Cathedral's Advent Carol Service.

Hereford - Hereford Cathedral School Chapel Choir

09/2018 - 07/2020

Performances in St Paul's Cathedral London, numerous performances in Hereford Cathedral, and a charity performance on the streets of Hereford to enthuse younger people into pursuing music.

Hereford Cathedral - Chorister

Hereford, Herefordshire

01/2015 - 07/2017

Sung in a choir of 10-15, rehearsing and performing 21 hours a week. Performances Include:

Three Choirs Festival 2015, 2016, 2017.

Performance for Prince Charles (as part of the Three Choirs Festival) in Buckingham Palace.

Evensong on BBC Radio 3, once for the Three Choirs Festival in 2015, and once again as a separate occasion.

St Mathew Passion (with external orchestra and soloists)

St John Passion (with external orchestra and soloists) - 2016

Christmas Oratorio (with external orchestra) - December 2017

Faure, Duruflé, Mozart Requiem (with external orchestras)

Premiere of Chilcott's Three Choirs Service; Magnificat & Nunc Dimittis which the composer attended.

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: Music

Grade Achieved: 9

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: Combined Science

Grade Achieved: 7

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: English Literature

Grade Achieved: 7

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: English Language

Grade Achieved: 7

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: Art and Design: Fine Art

Grade Achieved: 6

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: **History**Grade Achieved: **6**

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: Maths

Grade Achieved: 5

2020

Hereford Cathedral School

GCSE: **French**Grade Achieved: **5**

2017

Speech and Drama in Speaking

Verse and Prose: *Merit*

Recording of an album to be commercially sold on CD and digital formats.

The One in Royal David's City solo to commence the Nine Lessons and Carols service.

A one-week tour of around America, singing evensong in remote churches each day.